<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Untitled Data Science Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Untitled Data Science Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Bonanza: Misconceptions and Confidence Intervals</title>
      <link>/2020/10/29/probability-bonanza-misconceptions-and-confidence-intervals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/29/probability-bonanza-misconceptions-and-confidence-intervals/</guid>
      <description>h1 {text-align: center;}Getting a GripAside from Theranos, I don’t know of any topic that has more mystique surrounding and people putting far too much stock (pun intended) into it than p-values. A very-much related, and probably less understood, topic is that of confidence intervals, which are essentially the stock market of the statistics world: no one understands them, but we all have a ton of speculation about what they’re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Capitals the Largest Cities in Each State?</title>
      <link>/2020/07/19/states/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/19/states/</guid>
      <description>h1 {text-align: center;}Setting the StageMy girlfriend and I were talking the other day about how weird it is that most American states seem to have capitals that are not their largest city. Upon further discussion, I thought of large cities like Salt Lake City, Utah (where I live), that actually are the state capital and the largest city. So we really wanted to know ‘are there more of the largest cities in each state that aren’t the capital versus those that are?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/2020/07/05/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/05/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello, and thanks for visiting my blog! My name is Hal Svien; this is my data science blog where I’ll explore some data sets and answer questions that I find interesting. See the About section for more about me and my background, education, and my approach to this blog.
I’ll include my citations with every post, and you’ll notice some come up frequently. I’ll end up using books by Scott Baldwin, Rex Kline, Neil Salkind, and Rebecca Warner because they are very elaborative, often giving examples from simulation data or the like to show you why what they’re discussing is accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>